So we saw that if we ask these three questions. Well
所以我们看到 如果我们问这三个问题 那么
we needed three questions to be sure that we will find the
我们需要三个问题来确保我们可以找到
gold star, by opening box, but we don't need three questions.
金星并打开盒子 但我们并不需要三个问题
If we are little smarter about our questions, we only need 2.
如果我们更聪明一点 我们只需要2个问题
And the way to do it in 2 questions is to
而用2个问题做到这点 就是要
ask for questions that gives us more information. So the problem with
提出可以给我们更多信息的问题 所以
asking is that is it in the green box question first?
一开始询问 它是否在绿色盒子中 的问题
Is that three 3 4 of the time? The answer is no.
在3/4的时间中 答案会是 否
And if we're trying to use yes, no questions. Or we're trying to
如果我们尝试使用 是否问题 或者 我们正在尝试
use bits to get as much information as possible, what we want to do
使用比特来得到尽可能多的信息 我们想要做的
is ask questions where the answer is equally likely to be yes as
是询问这样的问题 答案是与否的概率
it is to be no. We want a question where half the time the
相等 我们想要这样的问题 有一半的时间
answer is yes and half the time the answer is no. If the
答案是肯定的 一半的时间答案是否定的 如果
question isn't like that, so if it's a question where it's no more
问题不是这样的 如果它是一个这样的问题 不再
often than it's yes, well then we could guess the answer is no
经常是肯定的 那么我们就可以猜出答案是否定的
and be right more than half the time. So we're not getting a full
并且有超过一半的机会回答正确 所以 我们没有在结果中得到
bit of information in the result, because we had a good chance
一整个比特的信息 因为我们有一个很好的机会
of being right without getting that answer. So we want to figure out
在没有获得答案的时候猜对 因此 我们要找出
questions where the answer is equally likely to be yes. As it
否定答案与肯定答案同等可能的问题
is to be no. So we could ask that as our first
因此 我们可以问这个作为我们的第一个
question. So we're going to ask, is the gold star in either the
问题 我们要问 金星是在绿色
green or the purple box? So the answer is yes if it's
盒子还是在紫色盒子中？答案是肯定的——如果它是
in one of those two boxes. The answer is no if it's
在这两个盒子中的一个 答案是否定的——如果它是
in either the blue or the red box. So, there are four boxes.
在蓝色或红色的盒子 那么 有四个盒子
For two of the boxes the answer is going to be
对于其中的两个盒子 答案将是肯定的
yes, so half the time the answer is yes. So that
所以一半的时间 答案是肯定的 那么这
means, we're gaining one full bit of information. If the answer
意味着我们获取了一个比特的信息 如果答案
is yes, we've learned that it's in either the green or
是肯定的 我们就了解到 它在绿色或者
the pop-, purple box. If the answer is no, we've learned
紫色的盒子 如果答案是否定的 我们了解到
that it's in either the blue or the red box. And
它在蓝色或红色的盒子里
so if the answer is yes, well now we need to
因此 如果答案是肯定的 那么现在我们需要
ask one more question. To figure out which box it's in.
再问一个问题 为了弄清楚它到底在哪个中
And that could be, is it in the green box?
这个问题可以是 它是否在绿色盒子？
And so, if we ask that question, if the answer is
那么 如果我们问这个问题 如果答案是
yes, well then we know it's in the green box. If
肯定的 那好 我们知道它在绿色盒子 如果
the answer is no, then we know it's in the purple
答案是否定的 那么我们就知道它在紫色盒子
box. We only needed two questions to get to the right
我们只需要两个问题 以获得正确的
box. And that's the same, if the answer was no to
答案 相同得 如果答案是否定的
this. Well then we can ask is it in the blue
那好 我们可以问它是否在蓝色
box? That's a yes no question. If the answer is yes,
盒子？这是一个是否问题 如果答案是肯定的
well then we know it's in the blue box.
那好 我们知道它在蓝色盒子
If the answer is no, then we know that it's
如果答案是否定的 那么我们就知道它
in the red box. So now, we can cover
在红色盒子 所以现在 我们可以覆盖
all four possible boxes. We didn't need three questions like
所有四种可能的盒子 我们并不需要三个问题
we did when we asked, is it in the green box, is it in the purple box, is it
像我们之前问过的那样 是否在绿色盒子 是否在紫色盒子 是否
in the blue box? We might have needed three
在蓝盒子 我们可能曾经需要三个
questions to determine the box, here we only needed two.
问题来定位箱子 这里我们只需要两个